<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>What's My Pro-Life Line?</title>
    <link>https://facebook.com/whatsmyprolifeline</link>
    <description>
      We suggest things you can say to promote and defend the pro-life position with love and kindness.
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
  <item><title>Who Will Adopt Unwanted Babies?</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies/</link><guid>a462e653-3b1f-4d22-9e43-c0f023009063</guid><pubDate>2019-12-29</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies-0-fb.png"&gt;We should all want kids to grow up in happy homes. Unfortunately, there really are a lot of *older* kids in the foster care system, many of whom are waiting to be adopted. These kids do face serious challenges. On the other hand, when *newborns* are placed for adoption, they go directly to adoptive families’ homes, generally without even entering the foster care system at all. Gently make sure your conversation partner understands the differences between these two situations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Should We Tell Women What to Do?</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/</link><guid>8dfdf906-d80f-4ee5-add8-71a9fe7fca98</guid><pubDate>2019-12-27</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do-0-fb.png"&gt;Remember to show compassion. Make it clear that this isn’t about punishing or oppressing women. We think men and women have equal value. We also think fetuses and adults have equal value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Should We Tell Women What to Do?</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/</link><guid>9ecaf8aa-7383-4077-a271-56bba7d7b9e6</guid><pubDate>2019-12-27</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do-0-fb.png"&gt;Remember to show compassion. Make it clear that this isn’t about punishing or oppressing women. We think men and women have equal value. We also think fetuses and adults have equal value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Let’s at Least Understand Each Other</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/lets-understand-each-other/</link><guid>2833db00-9951-487a-8ce3-cbe779b7fafa</guid><pubDate>2019-12-07</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/lets-understand-each-other/lets-understand-each-other-0-fb.png"&gt;We do want pro-choice people’s minds to change about abortion. (We want to establish a pro-life consensus!) But sometimes, someone just isn’t ready to change their mind. In that case, it’s good to at least learn about their views and help them to learn about ours. That way, we can strengthen our relationship with them, we can become better pro-life advocates, and we can give them a better impression of the pro-life movement. If we’re lucky, maybe their mind will change after all, or at least we’ll be in a better position to change their mind in the future.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That being said, if someone really doesn’t want to talk about abortion, don’t force it. You might end up doing more harm than good if you’re too pushy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/lets-understand-each-other/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_empathy</description></item><item><title>An Individual Life vs. Life in General</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/individual-vs-general-life/</link><guid>b6f14cc2-31f8-4117-aec2-0a605361b14a</guid><pubDate>2019-11-27</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/individual-vs-general-life/individual-vs-general-life-0-fb.png"&gt;When we say “life begins at conception,” we’re not talking about the beginning of life in general. We’re talking about the beginning of *an individual* life. From a purely biological standpoint, fertilization creates a new, unique, tiny, living organism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/individual-vs-general-life/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_lifebegins #WMPLL_biology</description></item><item><title>We Will Support You</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-will-support-you/</link><guid>8df97ae4-ec24-47c0-bf41-5e03194dee81</guid><pubDate>2019-11-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-will-support-you/we-will-support-you-0-fb.png"&gt;Pro-life pregnancy resource centers provide free or low-cost goods and services, often including pregnancy tests, sonograms, maternity clothes, diapers, counseling, and education. Familiarize yourself with pregnancy resource centers in your area so that you’re prepared to help.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-will-support-you/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society #WMPLL_buildeachotherup</description></item><item><title>Chickens Breathe</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/chickens-breathe/</link><guid>7279c7b1-bbce-4536-9825-2fbfb9585388</guid><pubDate>2019-11-02</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/chickens-breathe/chickens-breathe-1-fb.png"&gt;This is an example of the Equal Rights Argument. On all sides of the abortion debate, most people agree that those of us outside the womb have equal value. Ask what we have in common that makes us equal, and listen carefully to the answer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In this example, the proposed answer is that breathing air is what makes us equal. Many non-human animals such as roosters breathe air too. This is important, because most people agree that humans and roosters are not equals. To be clear, we’re not saying that animals shouldn’t have any protections. Animal abuse is wrong. We’re just saying that humans and roosters don’t have the same exact status. So breathing can’t be what makes us equals.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We think a good explanation for our equality is simply that we’re all living human organisms. A fetus is also a living human organism, so if we’re correct, then the fetus is a person with the same value as you and us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Check out this related collection of newsletters by Justice for All: http://doc.jfaweb.org/Training/JFAEqualRightsNewsletterCollection.pdf&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/chickens-breathe/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_personhood</description></item><item><title>Never Accept Rape</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/never-accept-rape/</link><guid>c197e004-f7c3-4ee7-b3f9-89c187d94098</guid><pubDate>2019-10-14</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/never-accept-rape/never-accept-rape-0-fb.png"&gt;Abortion, like rape, is an act of violence. With love and compassion, we should assist rape victims in nonviolent ways. For example, we should ensure that rape victims have access to counseling, and when a pregnant rape victim chooses to place her child for adoption, we should help with the process.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/never-accept-rape/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_rape #WMPLL_society #WMPLL_buildeachotherup</description></item><item><title>Care About People After Birth</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/care-about-people-after-birth/</link><guid>3957d2da-aee4-4869-8339-098aa3151cef</guid><pubDate>2019-10-03</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/care-about-people-after-birth/care-about-people-after-birth-1-fb.png"&gt;Faced with this accusation, some well-meaning pro-life advocates give an argument that abortion should be a higher priority than other issues. Instead, we think it’s more productive to reassure your conversation partner that you’re compassionate.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/care-about-people-after-birth/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Save Everyone From Abortion</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/save-everyone-from-abortion/</link><guid>b8a6737c-d523-4f7b-989d-b9d90061e472</guid><pubDate>2019-09-21</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/save-everyone-from-abortion/save-everyone-from-abortion-0-fb.png"&gt;We must outlaw abortion, but that’s not enough. We must take extra steps to safeguard women’s health. Pregnant women and their preborn children have equal value, and either one of them getting hurt is a tragedy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/save-everyone-from-abortion/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_womenshealth #WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_society</description></item></channel>
</rss>