<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>What's My Pro-Life Line?</title>
    <link>https://facebook.com/whatsmyprolifeline</link>
    <description>
      We suggest things you can say to promote and defend the pro-life position with love and kindness.
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
  <item><title>Save Everyone From Abortion</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/save-everyone-from-abortion/</link><guid>b8a6737c-d523-4f7b-989d-b9d90061e472</guid><pubDate>2019-09-21</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/save-everyone-from-abortion/save-everyone-from-abortion-0-fb.png"&gt;We must outlaw abortion, but that’s not enough. We must take extra steps to safeguard women’s health. Pregnant women and their preborn children have equal value, and either one of them getting hurt is a tragedy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/save-everyone-from-abortion/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_womenshealth #WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>We Should Care for Unwanted Children</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-should-care-for-unwanted-children/</link><guid>deb24056-7538-472d-823a-3bae141b557a</guid><pubDate>2019-08-31</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-should-care-for-unwanted-children/we-should-care-for-unwanted-children-1-fb.png"&gt;We don’t want any children to grow up unloved, but we don’t think that’s reason enough to kill people who are already alive. We should work to improve their lives, not end their lives.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Don’t expect this analogy on its own to change anyone’s mind. Pro-choice people usually feel that there’s an important difference between abortion and killing a two-year-old. The point of the analogy is just to bring those differences to the surface. Listen very carefully as they explain what they feel is the crucial difference between abortion and killing a two-year-old, and go from there.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They might point to something about the fetus herself. They might think abortion is similar to killing a plant or removing a tumor. In reality, abortion kills a living human person who deserves basic rights. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Instead of the fetus herself, they might point to something about the situation the fetus and mother are in. They might think abortion is similar to unplugging a ventilator or defending yourself against an assailant. In reality, pregnancy does not give a mother permission to kill her child. In fact, it gives her and her community an even *greater* duty to protect the child, compared to their ordinary duties to typical adults.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rarely, someone might bite the bullet and say to kill the two-year-old. In this case, we recommend that you drop the abortion topic until you can reach agreement about killing two-year-olds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-should-care-for-unwanted-children/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_TOT #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Be There For Abortion-Minded Women</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/be-there-for-abortion-minded-women/</link><guid>61181142-b84d-4cad-a16b-07ea15865e3d</guid><pubDate>2019-08-25</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/be-there-for-abortion-minded-women/be-there-for-abortion-minded-women-0-fb.png"&gt;Abortion is totally unacceptable, and your instinct might be to talk about everything wrong with it, but that’s often not the best approach. Instead, focus on the person standing in front of you and the challenges she’s facing. She’s probably afraid. Listen to her and try to understand her concerns first. Then prove to her through your kindness that you’re ready to support her through pregnancy. Be familiar with local life-affirming resources so you’re ready to thoroughly help her.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Although we don’t support abortion, we must support both pregnant women and post-abortive women. One way to support a pregnant woman is to persuade her to reject abortion. Tragically, though, sometimes our efforts fail. If she does get an abortion, we want her to feel safe talking to us again about abortion and her experience. Don’t turn your back on friends who have had abortions. Love them. Help them recognize the true nature of abortion. Help them heal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/be-there-for-abortion-minded-women/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_buildeachotherup</description></item><item><title>Mother and Child Are Equal</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/mother-and-child-are-equal/</link><guid>859c92ad-35be-4607-8968-ba04a06d709c</guid><pubDate>2019-08-13</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/mother-and-child-are-equal/mother-and-child-are-equal-1-fb.png"&gt;Be especially cautious when talking about this heartbreaking subject. Your conversation partner might personally know someone who experienced a life-threatening health problem while pregnant.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We find it helpful to talk about a concrete situation. One difficult situation is when a pregnant woman suffers from cancer somewhere in her reproductive system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It’s always wrong to *intentionally* attack the child, even for a noble goal like saving the mother’s life. However, it’s appropriate for doctors to treat the mother’s disease, even if those treatments have a risk of *unintentionally* harming the child. Thankfully, some approaches to treating pregnant cancer patients can potentially be effective while still giving the child a chance to thrive. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Still, in some cases, it can be morally acceptable to surgically remove a pregnant cancer patient’s uterus, even if the child isn’t viable yet. Tragically, this drastic measure ends the child’s life. However, it’s helpful to think of this operation as separate from abortion, because the *purpose* of the operation is to preserve life and health, not to attack anybody. The harm the child undergoes is not what benefits the mother.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/mother-and-child-are-equal/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_womenshealth #WMPLL_ethics</description></item><item><title>Distance Yourself From Harmful Pro-Life Actions</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/distance-yourself-from-harmful-pro-life-actions/</link><guid>d535785a-1442-4ee7-b137-cbffb654cbd3</guid><pubDate>2019-07-01</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/distance-yourself-from-harmful-pro-life-actions/distance-yourself-from-harmful-pro-life-actions-0-fb.png"&gt;Society should treat both pregnant women and preborn children with respect. We appreciate groups like Sidewalk Advocates for Life who gently encourage women considering abortion to leave the abortion facility and instead take advantage of life-affirming resources. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Abortion is completely unacceptable, but it’s not always time to make a pro-life argument. Love the person you’re talking to. Be gentle, especially if they’re upset. If they consider you to be an “enemy,” they might not be ready to think about new ideas you could present anyway. Conversations about emotionally charged topics like abortion are most productive when both parties are calm and open to new perspectives.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/distance-yourself-from-harmful-pro-life-actions/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_buildeachotherup #WMPLL_empathy #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Abortion vs. Not Donating Organs</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-vs-not-donating-organs/</link><guid>988a76c0-4831-4e9b-8741-ccecfa3449b3</guid><pubDate>2019-06-12</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-vs-not-donating-organs/abortion-vs-not-donating-organs-0-940.png"&gt;Some well-meaning pro-life advocates only focus on the nature of the preborn, but that’s not always helpful. Some pro-choice arguments, like the one in this example, attempt to show that abortion is okay *even if* a fetus has human rights.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are many differences between abortion and refraining from donating an organ, but one of the most important differences is this. When a patient waiting for an organ transplant dies, *her injury or illness* is what kills her. If you could have donated the organ and didn’t, you allowed her to die, but you didn’t kill her. To be clear, this tragic situation is very serious, and we should all carefully consider whether we are doing enough to assist those in need. However, declining to donate organs is not homicide. In contrast, when a fetus dies through elective abortion, *the act of abortion itself* is what kills her. Abortion is a violation of basic human rights.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Check out this related blog post by Pro-Life Humanists: http://www.prolifehumanists.org/unwanted-pregnancy-forced-organ-donation/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-vs-not-donating-organs/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_bodilyautonomy #WMPLL_ethics</description></item><item><title>Take Pro-Choice Ideas Seriously</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/take-pro-choice-ideas-seriously/</link><guid>d0da0742-c440-4431-8b24-663b3ce5c5ce</guid><pubDate>2019-06-08</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/take-pro-choice-ideas-seriously/take-pro-choice-ideas-seriously-0-940.png"&gt;Pro-choice people are our peers. Ultimately, we think the best arguments and evidence support the pro-life position, but you should take pro-choice arguments seriously. People defending abortion deserve genuine responses to the things they say. If we all try to understand each other, we’ll be in a better position to reach a consensus about abortion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/take-pro-choice-ideas-seriously/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_buildeachotherup</description></item><item><title>Push Forward to a Pro-Life Future</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future/</link><guid>d95d4b3e-2972-418c-8579-3642a39a4f0c</guid><pubDate>2019-06-01</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future-0-940.png"&gt;Unfortunately, people were treated badly in the past, and people are still treated badly today. Let’s work toward a future that is better than the past and better than the present. Let’s create a society that respects all human beings as equals, regardless of gender, sex, age, intelligence, or anything else.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Push Forward to a Pro-Life Future</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future/</link><guid>fbb783ef-284e-4116-a8ba-fe158c119d95</guid><pubDate>2019-06-01</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future-0-940.png"&gt;Unfortunately, people were treated badly in the past, and people are still treated badly today. Let’s work toward a future that is better than the past and better than the present. Let’s create a society that respects all human beings as equals, regardless of gender, sex, age, intelligence, or anything else.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/push-forward-to-a-pro-life-future/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Women Get Abortions for Real Reasons</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/women-get-abortions-for-real-reasons/</link><guid>770d3d65-4ca4-42f7-a335-7e6e79b41d28</guid><pubDate>2019-03-28</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/women-get-abortions-for-real-reasons/women-get-abortions-for-real-reasons-0-940.png"&gt;Pregnancy can be scary and difficult. Build common ground with your conversation partner by showing that you care about pregnant women too. As pro-life advocates, we think society should use nonviolent methods to support pregnant women. If you make that clear, your conversation partner will be more likely to take your anti-abortion stance seriously.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/women-get-abortions-for-real-reasons/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_empathy</description></item></channel>
</rss>