<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>What's My Pro-Life Line?</title>
    <link>https://facebook.com/whatsmyprolifeline</link>
    <description>
      We suggest things you can say to promote and defend the pro-life position with love and kindness.
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
  <item><title>Bringing a Child Into the World</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/bringing-child-into-world/</link><guid>88224529-d89a-45ff-84f8-51aad8076bf1</guid><pubDate>2020-10-12</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/bringing-child-into-world/bringing-child-into-world-0-fb.png"&gt;It’s okay not to feel ready to be a parent. Make it clear to your conversation partner that you don’t think an unprepared pregnant woman should just be left to fend for herself. Society should use nonviolent methods to support pregnant women. For example, we’re grateful for the adoption system. Placing a baby for adoption can be a great act of love toward that baby.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Fertilization brings a kid into the world; abortion kills a kid who is already alive.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/bringing-child-into-world/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_lifebegins #WMPLL_personhood #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Glad You’re Okay</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/glad-youre-okay/</link><guid>bb2a4f2d-aca8-4745-96e7-75938a0ee865</guid><pubDate>2020-07-15</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/glad-youre-okay/glad-youre-okay-1-fb.png"&gt;It’s not always time to make a pro-life argument. Remember to show compassion and listen to understand. Abortion is a really sensitive topic! Be prepared for any conversation to emotionally affect people, and understand that if someone is upset, they’re not prepared to think reasonably. They will probably reject any argument you make, and even view arguments as personal attacks. We don’t want to upset people, so when you’re talking with someone who may be emotionally affected by the conversation, it’s a good idea to spend a lot of time building trust and common ground. You may not even get to make a single argument in your first few conversations with someone! That’s okay. You’re still making positive progress even if all you’re doing is moving toward an environment where your conversation partner feels safe enough to think about what you’re saying with an open mind.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/glad-youre-okay/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_empathy</description></item><item><title>Men and Women Make Mistakes</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/men-and-women-make-mistakes/</link><guid>3e249011-c52f-48b7-b5c6-708494487e63</guid><pubDate>2020-07-12</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/men-and-women-make-mistakes/men-and-women-make-mistakes-0-fb.png"&gt;Being accused of mistrusting women can hurt. Try not to take personal offense. Faced with that accusation, well-meaning pro-lifers might be tempted to say something like, “It’s not about women, it’s about taking care of the baby.” The truth is, it’s about both. Defending the child of an abortion-minded woman means preventing her from making a particular choice. That’s okay! “To err is human” after all. We all need help sometimes making right choices.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Your pro-choice conversation partner probably recognizes the goodness of stopping someone from doing something horrendous. We think child abuse is a good example. Thankfully, there is widespread agreement that child abuse is never okay. As pro-lifers, we understand that the fetus is a small child, and ending their life is an extreme form of abuse, even if those involved have good intentions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Don’t expect their mind to change immediately. Pro-choice people usually feel that there’s some important difference between abortion and child abuse. Hopefully, they’ll respond by expressing more clearly what they disagree with you about. Do they think the fetus isn’t a child? In that case, it’s time to for a conversation about human biology and human value. Or maybe they think abortion doesn’t count as abuse. Then the two of you should discuss the ethics of violence and killing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/men-and-women-make-mistakes/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_ethics #WMPLL_womenshealth #WMPLL_bodilyautonomy #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Diverse People Deserve the Same Rights</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/diverse-people-deserve-the-same-rights/</link><guid>37f35f51-e466-4c73-9adb-83d31d212ec8</guid><pubDate>2020-06-07</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/diverse-people-deserve-the-same-rights/diverse-people-deserve-the-same-rights-1-fb.png"&gt;This is called the Equal Rights Argument. On all sides of the abortion debate, most people agree that those of us outside the womb have equal value. We think a good explanation for this equality is that we’re all members of the human species. The human fetus is also a member of the human species, so the fetus is a person with that same value. Most popular alternative explanations have troubling, unpopular implications. Here’s a related collection of newsletters by Justice for All: http://doc.jfaweb.org/Training/JFAEqualRightsNewsletterCollection.pdf&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/diverse-people-deserve-the-same-rights/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society #WMPLL_personhood</description></item><item><title>If They’re Surprised You’re Pro-Life</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/if-theyre-surprised-youre-pro-life/</link><guid>a2eefc9a-e8dd-4b9f-9163-d939f2a44e24</guid><pubDate>2020-05-20</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/if-theyre-surprised-youre-pro-life/if-theyre-surprised-youre-pro-life-0-fb.png"&gt;Don’t assume you know what someone thinks about abortion just because you know their background, what they think about other things, their personality, or anything else. The pro-life and pro-choice communities are both diverse.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Share your pro-life convictions with those around you. Be confident but not intimidating. Make it clear that you’re a safe person to talk to. Invite people into respectful abortion dialogue, but don’t force it or make them feel flustered.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/if-theyre-surprised-youre-pro-life/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society #WMPLL_buildeachotherup</description></item><item><title>We Know When Life Begins</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-know-when-life-begins/</link><guid>2d107686-1c19-4927-86af-1c28a12b5a8e</guid><pubDate>2020-01-03</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-know-when-life-begins/we-know-when-life-begins-1-fb.png"&gt;This is an important clarification question. Some well-meaning pro-life advocates only focus on the fact that a fetus is biologically alive, but that’s not always helpful. Sometimes people say “life” to mean “the life of a person”, and we need to be prepared to give an argument that every member of the human species is a valuable person.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/we-know-when-life-begins/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_lifebegins #WMPLL_biology #WMPLL_personhood</description></item><item><title>Who Will Adopt Unwanted Babies?</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies/</link><guid>a462e653-3b1f-4d22-9e43-c0f023009063</guid><pubDate>2019-12-29</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies-0-fb.png"&gt;We should all want kids to grow up in happy homes. Unfortunately, there really are a lot of *older* kids in the foster care system, many of whom are waiting to be adopted. These kids do face serious challenges. On the other hand, when *newborns* are placed for adoption, they go directly to adoptive families’ homes, generally without even entering the foster care system at all. Gently make sure your conversation partner understands the differences between these two situations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/who-will-adopt-unwanted-babies/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Should We Tell Women What to Do?</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/</link><guid>8dfdf906-d80f-4ee5-add8-71a9fe7fca98</guid><pubDate>2019-12-27</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do-0-fb.png"&gt;Remember to show compassion. Make it clear that this isn’t about punishing or oppressing women. We think men and women have equal value. We also think fetuses and adults have equal value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Should We Tell Women What to Do?</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/</link><guid>9ecaf8aa-7383-4077-a271-56bba7d7b9e6</guid><pubDate>2019-12-27</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do-0-fb.png"&gt;Remember to show compassion. Make it clear that this isn’t about punishing or oppressing women. We think men and women have equal value. We also think fetuses and adults have equal value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/should-we-tell-women-what-to-do/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Let’s at Least Understand Each Other</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/lets-understand-each-other/</link><guid>2833db00-9951-487a-8ce3-cbe779b7fafa</guid><pubDate>2019-12-07</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/lets-understand-each-other/lets-understand-each-other-0-fb.png"&gt;We do want pro-choice people’s minds to change about abortion. (We want to establish a pro-life consensus!) But sometimes, someone just isn’t ready to change their mind. In that case, it’s good to at least learn about their views and help them to learn about ours. That way, we can strengthen our relationship with them, we can become better pro-life advocates, and we can give them a better impression of the pro-life movement. If we’re lucky, maybe their mind will change after all, or at least we’ll be in a better position to change their mind in the future.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That being said, if someone really doesn’t want to talk about abortion, don’t force it. You might end up doing more harm than good if you’re too pushy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/lets-understand-each-other/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_empathy</description></item></channel>
</rss>